Now, let's look at the attention decoder and how it works at a very high level.
现在我们大致了解下注意力解码器的原理
At every time step,
在每个时间步
an attention decoder pays attention to
注意力解码器都根据语境因子
the appropriate part of the input sequence using the context factor.
关注输入序列的相应部分
How does the attention decoder know which of the parts
在每一步 注意力解码器如何知道
of the input sequence to focus on at each step?
要侧重于输入序列的哪个部分？
That process is learned during the training phase,
这个流程是在训练阶段学习的
and it's not just stupidly going sequentially from the first and the second to the third.
并不是简单地按顺序从第一个到第二个再到第三个
It can learn some sophisticated behavior.
它能够学习一些复杂的行为
Let's look at this example of translating a French sentence to an English one.
我们看一个将法语句子翻译成英语的示例
So let's say we have this input sentence in French.
假设有个这样的法语输入句子
Let's say we pass this to our encoder
将其传递给编码器
and now we're ready to look at each step in the decoding phase.
现在准备好查看解码阶段的每一步了
In the first step,
在第一步
the attention decoder would pay attention to the first part of the sentence.
注意力解码器会注意句子的第一部分
This is a trained model, right.
这是一个训练过的模型
So the more light the square is is the more attention that he
因此这个方格的亮度越高
gave to that word in particular.
就会越关注这个单词
So it pays attention to the first word and it outputs a first English word.
它注意到第一个单词并输出第一个英语单词
In the second step,
在第二步
it pays attention to the second word in
它注意到输入序列中的第二个单词
the input sequence and translates that word as well.
并翻译该单词
It goes on sequentially for about four steps
按顺序执行大约四步
and it produces reasonable English translation so far.
到目前为止生成了合理的英语翻译结果
Then something different happens here in the fifth step.
然后在第五步发生了不一样的情形
So, when we're generating the fifth word of the output,
当我们生成第五个单词时
the attention actually jumped two words to translate European.
注意力跳过两个单词 转变成翻译 European
So, we have zone, economique, europeenne,
因此有 zone economique europeenne
so on the English side it's not going to be in the same order.
在英语部分 不再是相同的顺序
So, europeenne is translated as
europeenne 翻译成了 European
European and then in the next step it focuses on the word before that,
然后在下一步 注意力跑到前面的单词上
economique, economic, and it focuses on zone and it outputs area.
economique economic 再侧重于 zone 输出 area
This is a case where the order of these words in the French language does not follow how
当这些单词在法语中的顺序和在英语中的不一样时
it would be ordered in
就会出现这种情形
the English language and the model was able to learn that just from a training data set.
模型能够根据训练数据集学习这种规律
The rest of the sentence goes on pretty much sequentially.
句子的剩余部分几乎都是按顺序进行的
So, this is a really cool example of how attention is able to make
这个示例很好地演示了注意力
these models focus on the right parts at the right moments based on what dataset we have.
如何使模型能够根据数据集在正确的时刻关注正确的部分